

#### **SOFTWARE + DATA**

A Stockholm, Sweden | ■igor@fer.st | %igor.fer.st | Oigorferst | Inigorferst

## Summary \_

I'm an experienced engineer who loves helping data scientists and analysts extract insights from complex, large-scale data. I've spent 13 years supporting technical data needs across a variety of domains (insurance, healthcare, capital markets, and others) as a data engineer, software engineer, and entrepreneur.

I have deep experience across the entire data stack: designing and building pipelines, ETL, data modeling, and executing analytics/data science projects. I focus on aligning technical work with business needs, and enjoy engaging directly with data users around requirement gathering and validation, training and upskilling, etc.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Epidemic Sound Stockholm, Sweden

Sr. Analytics Engineer Sept. 2023 - present

Epidemic's analytics engineering team owns our data warehouse and supports Epidemic's analysts and data scientists with tooling, data products, and expertise.

- Implemented new data warehouse deployment process that increased deployment frequency from twice a week to daily.
- Responsible for all data modeling and data integration in support of new CRM tool implementation.
- Technologies include: dbt, Airflow, BigQuery, Looker, Terraform

### **Bridgestone Mobility Solutions**

Stockholm, Sweden

SR. DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING/DATA ENGINEERING LEAD

Feb. 2021 - Aug. 2023

My startup Mobikit was acquired and its product incorporated into Bridgestone's software portfolio as a data-driven fleet risk management product for insurance carriers. At Bridgestone, I continued to lead data engineering and product development.

- Oversaw the design and implementation of our telematics data pipeline, with a focus on scalability, reliability, and observability.
- Managed globally distributed team of data and product engineers: hiring, onboarding, coaching, optimizing processes.
- Technologies include: Python (Django/DRF/pandas), SQL (PostgreSQL), AWS serverless/RDS/EC2/Kinesis/Glue, Docker

Mobikit Columbus (OH), USA

CO-FOUNDER/CTO

Jan. 2019 - Feb. 2021

Technical co-founder of a startup building a data analytics platform for large-scale vehicle telematics data. I oversaw data engineering, product development, and customer implementation.

- Architected and led development of data pipeline to ingest, harmonize, and enrich telematics data from heterogenous sources.
- Defined and validated data model with current and prospective customers.
- Oversaw design and development of platform's analytics features and executed ad-hoc analytics and data science projects.
- Contributed code across the entire stack, from data pipeline to ETL to application backend to UI.
- Grew and managed globally distributed team of developers.
- Raised funding, guided company to product-market fit, and exited successfully.
- Technologies include: Python (Django/DRF/pandas), SQL (PostgreSQL), AWS serverless/RDS/EC2, Docker, Javascript (React)

Root Insurance Columbus (OH), USA

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER/DATA ENGINEER

Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Worked at a growth-stage insuretech unicorn on various data-intensive projects.

- Prototyped a machine learning model to enhance insurance rate accuracy.
- Implemented support for new rating methodologies and executed historical backtests for rating changes.
- Python SME for engineering and actuarial teams.
- Technologies include: Ruby (Rails), Python (scikit-learn), Ansible

Enlace Health Columbus (OH), USA

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sept. 2014 - Feb. 2018

Enlace is a healthtech company building large-scale data analytics tools to support innovative models of healthcare delivery. I joined as an early employee working on the analytics platform, and transitioned to leading a cross-functional team building a care management and revenue cycle management product for surgical centers.

FEBRUARY 4, 2024 IGOR FERST

InSample San Francisco (CA), USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2014

First employee at a healthcare analytics startup building a cloud-based tool for statistical de-biasing of clinical experiments. Together with the CTO, I interviewed prospective customers, and designed and built the product prototype.

Google Mountain View (CA), USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2014

I was part of the conversion tracking team building tools that Google's customers use to understand the effectiveness of their ad spend. I implemented a novel conversion tracking visualization for the AdWords suite of analytics tools and developed enhancements to the Google Analytics machine learning algorithm for attribution modeling.

### **Palantir Technologies**

Palo Alto (CA), USA

FORWARD DEPLOYED ENGINEER

Jan. 2011 - Jan. 2013

I worked on Palantir Metropolis, a data integration and quantitative research platform for capital markets. I was a developer and product owner for the platform's visualization and reporting features, and was embedded with the platform's largest customer.

# Skills \_\_\_\_\_

**General** Data engineering, software engineering, product management, data science, technical leadership

**Languages** Python (primary), SQL, Javascript, Ruby, Java **Data** dbt, BigQuery, PostgreSQL, pandas, Looker

**Infrastructure** AWS, GCP, Docker, Airflow, Terraform, git

**Technical Expertise** Data science, data modeling, optimization, machine learning, graph algorithms

## **Education**

Cornell University Ithaca (NY), USA

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- PhD candidate in Applied Mathematics supported by a US National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship.
- Published original research in algorithms and optimization: https://tinyurl.com/ycheu4us

## **University of Waterloo**

Waterloo (Ontario), Canada

M.MATH. IN COMBINATORICS & OPTIMIZATION

### **University of Chicago**

Chicago (IL), USA

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS WITH HONORS

# **Volunteering**

Odesa Peace Fund Stockholm, Sweden

• General IT guidance and support for a US-based nonprofit providing humanitarian aid to Ukraine.

Hack OHI/O Columbus (OH), USA

• Twice served as judge and mentor for Ohio State University's student hackathon.

### United Schools Network Columbus (OH), USA

• Designed and taught a three month after-school programming course for middle-school students.